Guide to the Leo Bogart Papers, 1912-2010 and undated RL.10146
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Series, 1914-2005 and undated, 84 boxes
  The Writings and Speeches Subseries documents 149 speeches; 195 published articles; 14 books; book chapters and contributions; and other written materials Bogart produced over his career. Also includes articles for a monthly column in Presstime that Bogart wrote from 1989-2005. The subseries is divided in five sections: Speeches, Articles, Books, Book chapters and contributions, and Unpublished writings and drafts. Writings are arranged chronologically by date of publication, or for unpublished writings, creation date. Speeches are arranged chronologically by date of delivery.
  - Biographical Materials Subseries, 1949-2005 and undated
    Documents milestones and activities in Bogart's professional life, and includes clippings; interviews; correspondence; schedules; scrapbooks; and resumes. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Clippings, 1949-2000 and undated, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Interviews
      - In Aura Research Report (Japan), undated (Box 6)
      - Interview, The Eyes Have It: Leo Bogart of the Newspaper Advertising Bureau, in Madison Avenue, June 1983 (Box 6)
    - Meeting schedules, 1972-1988 (Box 6)
    - Membership rosters, 1964-2003 (Box 6)
    - Obituary, Adiós al Mítico in Nuestro Tiempo, 2005 (Box 6)
    - Newspaper Advertising Bureau
      - Congratulation letters (promotion), 1965-1966 (Box 6)
      - Retirement clippings and correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 6)
      - Retirement scrapbook, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Resumes and bibliographies, circa 1954-1988 (Box 7)
  - Conferences & Meetings Subseries, 1948-2005
    Documents Bogart's participation in conferences and meetings. Bogart participated in these events in a number of ways, including organizing conferences; serving on panel discussions; and giving informal remarks. For written speeches by Bogart and related materials, see the Writings and Speeches Subseries. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1948 Oct. 21-22, Standard Oil (New Jersey) Public Relations Conference (Box 7)
    - 1949 Nov. 21-22, Standard Oil (New Jersey) Public Relations Conference (Box 7)
    - 1952 Jan. 11-25, International Public Opinion Research conference on AUERG Research Problems prepared for Air University; Paris, France (Box 7)
    - 1956 Nov. 6, Kansas chapter of the AMA meeting (Box 7)
    - 1956 Dec. 27-29, Speech Association of America convention (Box 7)
    - 1957 Apr. 2-5, Columbia University conference on Strategies and Techniques of School-Community Relations (Box 7)
    - 1959 Apr. 29-30 International Advertising Association convention (Box 7)
    - 1960 June 15-17, AMA conference (Box 7)
    - 1963 Mar. 28, Marketing Science Institute seminar (Box 7)
    - 1964 May 5, Seminar on The Public and Private Interests in Marketing: Are They Compatible (Box 7)
    - 1965 May 11, Marketing Association of Canada meeting (Box 7)
    - 1965 Sept. 5-9, European Society for Opinion Surveys and Market Research/WAPOR conference (Box 7)
    - 1965 Oct. 27, General Electric market research seminar (Box 7)
    - 1966 Apr. 1-3, Conference on Behavioral Science and the Mass Media (Box 7)
    - 1966 May 25-29, Latin American WAPOR conference (Box 7)
    - 1966 Oct. 13, Akron, Ohio Ad Club meeting (Box 7)
    - 1966 Nov. 1, Retail Research Society meeting (Box 7)
    - 1967 Jan. 17, Norfolk Ad Club meeting (Box 7)
    - 1967 June 7-9, Conference on Behavioral Science and Family Planning (Box 7)
    - 1967 June 25-30, ANPA research seminar (Box 7)
    - 1967 Sept. 18, Atlanta Ad Club meeting (Box 7)
    - 1967 Oct. 6, Louisville, Kentucky Ad Club meeting (Box 7)
    - 1967 Oct. 11, Portland Ad Club meeting (Box 7)
    - 1967 Oct. 27-31, AMA conference (Box 7)
    - 1968 Jan. 18, TV and World Affairs conference (Box 7)
    - 1968 Feb. 1, Columbia University seminar on Problems of Media Management (Box 7)
    - 1968 Oct. 23, McGraw-Hill Research Managers' seminar (Box 7)
    - 1969 Mar. 30-Apr. 1, Boston Globe Newspaper of the Future meeting (Box 7)
    - 1969 Sept. 17, Defining the Markets of the 1970's seminar (Box 7)
    - 1970 May 19, INPA meeting (Box 7)
    - 1970 June, Johannesburg, South Africa trip (Box 7)
    - 1970 Nov. 19, Washington Society of Associations Executives luncheon (Box 7)
    - 1971 Mar. 25, Informing Tomorrow's Skeptical Consumers seminar (Box 7)
    - 1971 Apr. 16, National Research Council Division of Behavioral Sciences meeting on media research (Box 7)
    - 1971 Oct. 25-27, Australian Association of National Advertisers (Box 7)
    - 1972 June 7, Postal rates seminar (Box 7)
    - 1972 Nov. 19-20, Conference on Communication and Drug Abuse (Box 7)
    - 1973 Jan. 8, NRMA convention (Box 7)
    - 1973 Mar. 11-14, National Conference for University Professors of Advertising (Box 7)
    - 1973 Aug. 27-30, ASA annual meeting (Box 7)
    - 1973 Oct. 24-26, Television and Marketing in South Africa convention (Box 7)
    - 1973 Dec. 17-20, Conference on Television; Jerusalem, Israel (Box 8)
    - 1974 Apr. 28-May 1, American Academy of Advertising conference (Box 8)
    - 1975 Feb. 27, Copley Newspapers conference (Box 8)
    - 1975 Apr. 24-26, American Advertising Federation convention (Box 8)
    - 1975 Nov. 5-6, Ford Foundation conference on television (Box 8)
    - 1975 Nov. 5-7, Television Research Priorities conference (Box 8)
    - 1976 May 3-5, ANPA convention (Box 8)
    - 1976 June 13-15, Graphic Arts Marketing Information Service (Box 8)
    - 1976 June 23, Cox Newspapers' Star Trek meeting (Box 8)
    - 1976 Sept. 9, Aspen Institute Program on Communications and Society (Box 8)
    - 1976 Oct. 6-9, O Globo meeting (Box 8)
    - 1976 Oct. 20, ABC annual meeting (Box 8)
    - 1976 Nov.9-10, Big Ten newspapers meeting (Box 8)
    - 1977 Jan. 19, Woodrow Wilson Center dialogue on What is the Future of Big City Newspapers? (Box 8)
    - 1977 Feb. 14-24, New Zealand Newspapers Limited trip (Box 8)
    - 1977 May 19-22, AAPOR conference (Box 8)
    - 1977 July 28-29, Andiarios seminar on La Prensa Como Medio Publicitario; Bogotá, Colombia (Box 8)
    - 1977 Sept. 18-21, Cox Newspapers' Star Trek meeting (Box 8)
    - 1978 Feb. 14-15, Big Eleven newspapers meeting (Box 8)
    - 1978 Mar. 9, Reading Skills and Habits seminar (Box 8)
    - 1978 Apr. 9-12, ASNE conference (Box 8)
    - 1978 May 8-17, Australia trip (Box 8)
    - 1978 Aug. 28-Sept. 1, IAPA seminar (Box 8)
    - 1979 Mar. 16, Market Research Council meeting (Box 8)
    - 1979 Apr. 23-26, IAPA seminar; San José, Costa Rica (Box 8)
    - 1979 Aug. 5-8, AEJ convention (Box 8)
    - 1979 Oct. 21-24, Eastern INPA regional conference (Box 8)
    - 1980 May 29-June 1, AAPOR conference (Box 8)
    - 1980 Oct. 15-30, International Center for Higher Studies of Journalism for Latin America seminar; Quito, Ecuador (Box 8)
    - 1980 Oct. 22-28, De Standaard meeting; Brussels, Belgium (Box 8)
    - 1980 Oct. 23-26, Society of Newspaper Designers workshop (Box 8)
    - 1981 Jan 13, AMA conference (Box 8)
    - 1981 Mar. 4-6, ANPA meeting (Box 8)
    - 1981 May 4-6, ANPA convention (Box 8)
    - 1981 May 18, INPA conference (Box 8)
    - 1981 May 28-31, AAPOR conference (Box 8)
    - 1981 June 6-10, ANPA production conference (Box 8)
    - 1981 Aug. 10-11, AEJMC meetings (Box 8)
    - 1981 Aug. 27, Lee Enterprises meeting (Box 8)
    - 1981 Oct. 28, AAPOR meeting (Box 8)
    - 1981 Nov. 2-3, National Association of Educational Broadcasters conference (Box 8)
    - 1981 Nov. 4, ABC annual meeting (Box 8)
    - 1982 Jan. 8, American Association for the Advancement of Science annual meeting (Box 8)
    - 1982 Jan. 25-26, INAME education seminar (Box 8)
    - 1982 Mar. 3, Rampano College Master Lecture series (Box 8)
    - 1982 Mar. 25, Cox Newspapers editors meeting (Box 8)
    - 1982 May 19, WAPOR conference (Box 8)
    - 1982 June 3-4, Universidad de Navarra seminar, Spain (Box 8)
    - 1982 June 14, Scripps-Howard general managers meeting (Box 8)
    - 1982 July 25-28, AEJMC convention (Box 8)
    - 1982 Oct. 20-21, Conference Board marketing conference (Box 8)
    - 1983 Mar. 16-19, Committee On Research Development meeting (Box 8)
    - 1983 Mar. 22-23, Automotive meetings (Box 8)
    - 1983 Mar. 24, American Advertising Federation Inter-Association Council meeting (Box 8)
    - 1983 May 19-22, AAPOR conference (Box 8)
    - 1983 July 21, Milwaukee Journal meeting (Box 8)
    - 1983 Nov. 4, APME meeting (Box 9)
    - 1983 Nov. 14-16, Evening News Association management seminar (Box 9)
    - 1984 Feb. 16-18, Annenberg Scholars conference (Box 9)
    - 1984 Feb. 25-28, Inland Daily Press Association meeting (Box 9)
    - 1984 Apr. 4-7, Press '84 conference; Berlin, Germany (Box 9)
    - 1984 May 11, AdCraft Club meeting (Box 9)
    - 1984 May 17-20, AAPOR conference (Box 9)
    - 1984 Sept. 22-25, Market Research Society of Australia convention (Box 9)
    - 1984 Nov. 16, NYU Department of Journalism seminar (Box 9)
    - 1984 Nov. 30, American Marketing Association meeting (Box 9)
    - 1985 Feb. 18-21, Copley Newspapers conference (Box 9)
    - 1985 Feb. 19, Media Research Club meeting (Box 9)
    - 1985 Mar., ANPA Conference on Minorities (Box 9)
    - 1985 Sept. 13, Consortium of Social Science Associations seminar (Box 9)
    - 1985 Dec. 3, AAPOR meeting (Box 9)
    - 1985 Dec. 6-8, Conference on Communications Research: What, Why, and How? (Box 9)
    - 1986 Feb. 9, History of Mass Communication Research study group; Gannett Center, Columbia University (Box 9)
    - 1986 Feb. 13, Universidad de Navarra seminar, Spain (Box 9)
    - 1986 Mar. 6-8, Annenberg Scholars program conference (Box 9)
    - 1986 Mar. 16-19, ARF conference (Box 9)
    - 1986 Apr. 2-5, Committee On Research Development meeting (Box 9)
    - 1986 May 15-18, AAPOR conference (Box 9)
    - 1986 May 19, Aspen Institute symposium (Box 9)
    - 1986 June 5-6, IFRA symposium on Colour in the Newspaper (Box 9)
    - 1986 Aug. 30-Sept. 3, ASA annual meeting (Box 9)
    - 1986 Oct. 2-4, Bogotá, Colombia meeting (Box 9)
    - 1986 Nov. 13-14, New Jersey Press Association convention (Box 9)
    - 1987 Apr. 4-7, Committee On Research Development meeting (Box 9)
    - 1987 Apr. 5-8, Newspaper Research Council conference (Box 9)
    - 1987 May 14-17, AAPOR conference (Box 9)
    - 1987 Sept. 22-23, International Media Forum, Buenos Aires (Box 9)
    - 1987 Oct. 7-10, Committee On Research Development meeting (Box 9)
    - 1987 Nov. 9, International Association for Newspaper and Media Technology seminar (Box 9)
    - 1987 Dec. 9, New England Newspaper Association National Advertising Seminar (Box 9)
    - 1987, Cox Newspapers senior management conference (Box 9)
    - 1988 Mar. 21, Technology and Audience Study Group (Box 9)
    - 1988 Apr. 21, Pennsylvania Newspaper Publishers Association conference (Box 9)
    - 1988 May 19-22, AAPOR conference (Box 9)
    - 1988 May 22-25, International Newspaper Marketing Association conference (Box 9)
    - 1988 May, ANPA Circulation and Readership Committee meeting (Box 9)
    - 1988 July 31-Aug. 3, INAME conference (Box 9)
    - 1988 Aug. 7-9, ANPA Newspaper Adult Literacy workshop (Box 9)
    - 1988 Sept. 15-17, Perspectives on International Communications conference (Box 9)
    - 1988 Sept. 27, German Newspaper Publishers Association seminar (Box 9)
    - 1988 Sept. 28-30, Pennsylvania Newspaper Publishers Association annual meeting (Box 9)
    - 1988 Oct. 8-10, Landmark Editors' Meeting (Box 9)
    - 1988 Oct. 13-16, Committee On Research Development meeting (Box 9)
    - 1988 Dec., Canadian Pulp and Paper Association meeting (Box 9)
    - 1989 Feb. 27, AAPOR memorial service for Paul Sheatsley (Box 9)
    - 1989 July 3-13, International Journalism Day at San Sebastian, Spain (Box 9)
    - 1989 July 31, Newspaper Publishers' Association conference; Christchurch, New Zealand (Box 9)
    - 1989 Oct. 25, Houston Chronicle symposium (Box 9)
    - 1990 Mar. 4-7, IAPA midyear meeting; Managua, Nicaragua (Box 9)
    - 1990 Apr. 5, IFRA symposium on Advertising: Marketing and Technology; Nice, France (Box 9)
    - 1990 May 21-23, World Congress of Newspaper Publishers; Copenhagen, Denmark (Box 10)
    - 1991 Jan. 31, Markle Commission on the Media and the Electorate planning meeting (Box 10)
    - 1991 Oct. 20-23, International Newspaper Financial Executives annual convention (Box 10)
    - 1991 Nov., Universidad de Navarra conferences, Pamplona, Spain (Box 10)
    - 1992 May 15-19, AAPOR/WAPOR conference (Box 10)
    - 1993 Mar. 2-3, IFRA symposium; Hamburg, Germany (Box 10)
    - 1994 Mar., Spain trip (Box 10)
    - 1994, Latin America trip (Box 10)
    - 1995 Feb., Tunisia and Jordan trip (Box 10)
    - 1995 Mar. 20-24, Print Islam and Civil Pluralism conference (Box 10)
    - 1995 Apr. 5, Los Angeles Times New Media Roundtable (Box 10)
    - 1996 Nov. 10-13, WAPOR conference on public opinion in Asia; Hong Kong, China (Box 10)
    - 1996, Sociedad Española de Marketing Periodistico seminar (Box 10)
    - 1997 Apr. 17-18, World Association of Newspapers sales conference; Cannes, France (Box 10)
    - 2002 May 16-19, AAPOR/WAPOR conference on Strengthening Our Communities (Box 10)
    - 2004 Apr. 1, Fordham Business School and Columbia Institute for Tele-Information conference (Box 10)
    - 1956-2005, Miscellaneous conferences and meetings materials (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Subseries, 1956-2005 and undated
    Consists of general and topical professional correspondence divided into five categories: Academic, Newspapers and print media, Organizations and businesses, People, and Miscellaneous. Arranged alphabetically.
    - General correspondence, 1956-2003 and undated, 7 folders (Box 11)
    - Academic
      - Columbia University, 1972-1990 (Box 11)
      - Harvard University, 1968-1981 (Box 11)
      - New York University, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
      - Northwestern University, 1970 (Box 11)
      - Universidad de Navarra; Pamplona, Spain, 1979-1997 (Box 11)
      - University of Chicago, 1974-1981 (Box 11)
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1968-1975 (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous academic correspondence, 1957-1994 (Box 11)
    - Newspapers and print media (Box 12)
      - Boston Globe, 1977-1982 (Box 12)
      - Columbia Journalism Review, 1987-1988 (Box 12)
      - Editor & Publisher, 1972-1986 (Box 12)
      - Gannett Newspapers, 1978-1983 (Box 12)
      - Harte-Hanks Newspapers, 1978-1986 (Box 12)
      - Harvard Business School Press, 1997 (Box 12)
      - Knight Ridder Newspapers, 1977-1989 (Box 12)
      - Los Angeles Times, 1982-1988 (Box 12)
      - Milwaukee Journal, 1981-1989 (Box 12)
      - Minneapolis Star & Tribune, 1964-1979 (Box 12)
      - New York News, 1985-1987 (Box 12)
      - New York Post, 1974-1977 (Box 12)
      - The New York Times, 1969-1988 (Box 12)
      - Newhouse Newspapers, 1982 (Box 12)
      - Ottaway Newspapers, 1982-1986 (Box 12)
      - Roanoke Times and World News, 1985 (Box 12)
      - Saturday Review, 1969 (Box 12)
      - The Washington Post, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Organizations and businesses
      - Agencia Estado, 1996 (Box 12)
      - Andiarios; Bogotá, Colombia, 1990-1992 (Box 12)
      - Annenberg Foundation Trust, 2005 (Box 12)
      - Association of National Advertisers, 1967 (Box 12)
      - Census Bureau, 1969 (Box 12)
      - Colgate-Palmolive Company, 1986-1987 (Box 12)
      - Hanson, Cobb, O'Brien and Tucker law offices, 1968 (Box 12)
      - Hill and Knowlton, Inc., 1977 (Box 12)
      - Institute for the Future, 1971 (Box 12)
      - International Broadcast Institute, 1969-1970 (Box 12)
      - International Paper Company, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
      - Lee Enterprises, 1982-1984 (Box 12)
      - Library of Congress Center for the Book, 1978-1985 (Box 12)
      - Markle Foundation, 1972 (Box 12)
      - McCann-Erickson, 1982-1986 (Box 12)
      - Media General, Inc., 1979-1984 (Box 12)
      - Media Records, Inc., 1985-1986 (Box 12)
      - Newspaper Association of America, 1992 and undated (Box 12)
      - Newspaper Research Council, 1985-1989 (Box 12)
      - Newsprint Information Committee, 1978-1989 (Box 12)
      - Obor, Inc., 1975-1989 (Box 12)
      - Print Institute, 1976 (Box 12)
      - Radio Advertising Bureau, 1976-1978 (Box 12)
      - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 1952-1978 (Box 12)
      - Simmons Market Research Bureau, 1969-1986 (Box 12)
      - Smithsonian Institution, 1970 (Box 12)
      - 21st Century Comics project, 1982 (Box 12)
    - People
      - Abeles, Ronald, 1977 (Box 12)
      - Bagdikian, Ben H., 1969-1976 (Box 12)
      - Blum, Milton, 1969 (Box 12)
      - Carlson, Bob, 1972-1974 (Box 12)
      - Douglas, James, 1978 (Box 12)
      - Gorriti, Gustavo, 1997 (Box 12)
      - Graceras, Ulises, 1970-1980 (Box 12)
      - Johnson, Tom, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
      - Krugman, Herbert, 1973 (Box 12)
      - Markel, Lester, 1976-1977 (Box 12)
      - Mayer, Martin, 1969 (Box 12)
      - Michiewicz, Ellen, 1992 (Box 12)
      - Ralis, Max, 1972-1976 (Box 12)
      - Ratner, Victor, undated (Box 12)
      - Siepmann, Charles, 1968-1973 (Box 13)
      - Templeton, Lee, 1983-1991 (Box 13)
      - Williams, Fred, 1974-1984 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Advertising museum proposal, 2002 (Box 13)
      - Automotive, 1981 (Box 13)
      - Commission on Violence, 1968 (Box 13)
      - Direct mail, 1984-1985 (Box 13)
      - Discussion of Ruth Clark study on newspaper research, 1998 (Box 13)
      - International correspondence, 1974-1989 (Box 13)
      - Letters to the editors, 1982-1997 (Box 13)
      - Literacy
        - Ad Council literacy campaign, 1986 (Box 13)
        - General correspondence, 1977-1988 (Box 13)
      - Newspaper rates/pricing, 1972-1983 (Box 13)
      - Public issues presentation, 1971 (Box 13)
      - U.S. Office of Education Civil Rights Committee, 1964 (Box 13)
  - Early Career Subseries, 1947-1961 and undated
    Documents Bogart's professional career from 1951-1960, during which time Bogart worked as a Fulbright Research Fellow, and as a advertising and marketing researcher with Standard Oil Company of New Jersey; McCann-Erickson; and Revlon, Inc. The series includes the paper Bogart wrote as a Fulbright Fellow, Les Algérians en France; research on radio program listeners; and Revlon materials on quiz show fraud during the 1950s. Arranged topically and therein alphabetically.
    - General (Box 14)
      - Newspaper basics materials, 1954-1961 (Box 14)
      - University instruction application, 1950 (Box 14)
    - Fulbright Research Fellowship
      - Les Algérians en France
        - Les Algérians en France, in Français et Immigrés, tome 2, 1952 (Box 14)
        - Background materials, 1951 and undated (Box 14)
      - Algeria clippings, 1953 (Box 14)
      - Cahiers Nord-Africains booklets, 1950 (Box 14)
    - McCann-Erickson
      - Activation research, 1957 (Box 14)
      - An Evaluation of a U.S. Information Campaign in Salonica, Greece, 1953, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Life insurance study, 1956 (Box 14)
      - McCann-Erickson resignation correspondence, 1958-1969 (Box 14)
      - Media planning materials, 1955 and undated (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1955-1958 and undated (Box 14)
    - Revlon
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1956-1960 and undated (Box 14)
      - Quiz show fraud materials, 1959-1961 and undated (Box 14)
    - Standard Oil (New Jersey)
      - Aruba Oil materials, 1947-1950 and undated (Box 14)
      - Clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 14)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1952 (Box 14)
      - International public opinion research materials, 1948-1950 (Box 14)
      - Jersey's Publications Program and the College Teacher: A Report on a Field Study, 1951 (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1950 and undated (Box 15)
      - Notes, undated (Box 15)
      - Opinion Research in Public Relations Work: An Introductory Manual, 1949 (Box 15)
      - Outside research summaries, 1949-1950 (Box 15)
      - Public Opinion and Point Four, circa 1951 (Box 15)
      - Public relations conference minutes, 1949 (Box 15)
      - Radio studies
        - Alex Young program public relations study, 1952 (Box 15)
        - An Analysis of Listener Mail for the World Wide Broadcasting Foundation, 1950 (Box 15)
        - Average audience bar graph, 1947 (Box 15)
        - Elmira radio study materials, 1950 and undated (Box 15)
        - The Listeners Write to the Philharmonic, 1949-1975 (Box 15)
        - Studying the Effectiveness of Institutional Radio Advertising, undated (Box 15)
        - A 'Weekend with Music' in Rapid City, South Dakota, 1949 (Box 15)
        - 'Wheels of Oil' in Tulsa, Oklahoma: A Radio Listening Survey, 1950 (Box 15)
      - Speeches
        - Measuring Influence of an Institutional Radio Program presentation, 1951 (Box 15)
        - Public relations conference talk, circa 1951 (Box 15)
  - Late Career Subseries, 1988-2005 and undated
    After Bogart retired from the Newspaper Advertising Bureau, he was nominated a fellow with the Gannett Center for Media Studies for the 1989-1990 academic year. As a fellow, Bogart received support while completing his book Commercial Culture: The Media System and the Public Interest. For materials related to this book, see the Writings and Speeches Subseries. Bogart continued a relationship with the Gannett Center, which became financially independent from the Gannett Broadcasting Group in 1991 and was renamed the Freedom Forum Media Studies Center. On behalf of the Freedom Forum, Bogart advised the Oakland Tribune on how to restructure their business in 1991 and organized a newspaper advertising workshop in Russia and Eastern Europe in 1992.
    Bogart spent much of his late career sharing his newspaper industry and mass media expertise. As Director and Senior Consultant for Innovation International Media Consulting Group, Bogart advised newspapers, particularly in Spain, Latin America, Russia, and Eastern Europe; and assessed the state of newspapers and mass media for Innovation publications and conferences. Bogart also shared his knowledge about the mass media with attorneys as a media expert in two very public trials in the 1990s, Chandler v. Jackson (Michael Jackson child molestation lawsuit) and Valenzuela v. Hughes Aircraft Company (TCE groundwater contamination lawsuit in Tuscon, Arizona).
    Slides of presentations given at the Freedom Forum workshop and photographs of the trip are located in the Photographs and Slides Series. Presentation scripts are in Russian and English and slide text is in Russian. Videocassette tapes of media coverage of Michael Jackson and TCE groundwater contamination in Arizona are located in the Audiovisual Materials section. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Election day project, Joan Shorenstein Center, 2000-2003 (Box 16)
    - Gannett Center/Freedom Forum
      - Eastern Europe and Russia Press Marketing Project
        - Clippings and notes, 1991-1992, 2 folders (Box 16)
        - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 16)
        - Itineraries, contact lists, and receipts, 1992 (Box 16)
        - Workshop presentation scripts, 1992-1993, 2 folders (Box 16)
        - Writings, 1992 (Box 16)
      - Gannett Center Fellowship
        - Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 16)
        - The Future of Information symposium, 1990
          - Contributors' materials (Box 16)
          - Correspondence (Box 16)
          - The Future of Information monograph project, 1990-1994 (Box 17)
        - Printed materials
          - Covering the Campaign '88, circa 1988 (Box 17)
          - News and the New World Order, 1990 (Box 17)
          - Miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 17)
      - Seminars and presentations
        - Fellows seminar transcript, 1990 (Box 17)
        - Speech notes, 1989-1990 (Box 17)
        - Seminar and meeting materials, 1991-1997 (Box 17)